I managed to write for like 433 odd
different niches, markets, and
industries. There was a collagen
supplement company in uh Germany and
they had four launches prior, but every
time they did a launch, they would lose
about €200,000 every single time. And
this is where the creative strategy
comes in. Like we got off the call,
they're like, "We're launching in 2
weeks. It's in German. How quickly can
you get the copy done?" So I had to
write the copy within 3 days, have it
translated to German, have it to the
graphic designer, have it ready with the
products and shipped out in that time
period. That company that I worked with
in Germany, they sold for 165 million.
Not bad at all. But to be fair, that is
what an original copywriter was. We were
creative strategists at the very
beginning. Most people don't even think
about this. Creative strategy was part
of copywriting because it's knowing how
to pivot and use different angles and
how to use different strategies for an
audience. If you really want to have a
great idea of what a good creative
strategist is, David Oglevie is like the
number one person that comes to mind.
Well, he's a copywriter. No, he's a
creative strategist because if you look
at what he does, he comes up with ideas
and then pitches the idea and then has
his department create [music] the idea.
He is the definition of a creative
strategist. I remember talking to a few
of my friends where they were like,
"Yeah, dude. If you stop selling to
marketers and just start selling to
regular people, you will make way more
money." Marketers know all the tricks,
so you now need to pull out new tricks
and new secrets and new things that they
haven't seen before. Whereas selling to
an everyday person who has never seen
this [__] They're like, "Holy [__]
this is like magic. What are you doing?
This is so incredible." Think about how
easy that is. The stuff that we do on
hard mode is easy for us on ecom. If you
were told to write a [music] 30 email
welcome sequence or a 30 email sequence
for info, that's hard. 30 emails for
like econ. That's like those emails
could literally be one page. Hey, thanks
so much for joining our mailing list.
We'll be sending you some really cool
stuff. In the meantime, have a look at
this, including stories. Go buy our
product if you really like it. Take
care. Thanks. Bye. One of your guys,
Pepe, I was I was helping him out. He
started using emails for his client.
They were making 8,000 a month on
emails. After he entered the
conversation, just did a couple [music]
of tweaks, they made $80,000 afterwards.
>> Not bad.
>> It's so easy. It's soing easy.
>> All right, so I'm here with a man who
needs no introduction, Adela. How you
doing, man?
>> Hey. Hey. Thanks for having me. I'm back
on, man.
>> Look at us sipping our our drinks over
here.
>> So, we're talking about credit strategy.
be talking about how to how to scale
brands, how to make a lot of money. I
know we've been talking about a lot of
the stuff privately um with my private u
you know copyrightiting mentees and just
showing them the ropes of like how to
yeah do do what we do. But I thought
let's have another conversation and put
it on YouTube and and share the stuff
that people need to hear because you
know creative strategy for many people
they think it's this like new thing
where everybody's kind of like oh you
know create a strategy but that's what
copyriters originally did years and
years ago like creative strategy is is
just a new name for something that we've
been doing for a very long time. I mean
you've been a copyriter for you've been
writing copy for like what two decades
>> 24 years 24 years. Yeah.
>> Yeah. long ass time. Um, but so it's
kind of interesting because whenever I
hear the term creative strategy, it's
people used it as a way of masking what
the term copywriter is because again the
last conversation we had last year,
which is also ironically funny that I
was in Asia, you were in Africa. Now I'm
in Africa and you're in Asia. So we're
actually recording this just with the
humor of it all. Um, but what we
actually discussed last year was like
how I don't really see a lot of
copywriters
being able to hold up the title of
copywriter from like the old school
because of course they they kind of lost
their way. They only like focus on one
area instead of the entire thing. And
creative strategy is the same thing.
Creative strategy was part of
copywriting like the original part
because it's knowing how to pivot and
use different angles and how to use
different strategies for an audience.
Like for instance, if and we were
talking about this right before we
jumped on. If you are using a supplement
company, for instance, a supplement
company that is using the exact same
hook, angle, ideiation, and um
marketplace, they're all saying the same
thing, trying to sell the same product
at the same time. How do you stand out?
And people are like, "Oh, it's the story
I'm telling." I'm like, "Yeah, you're
telling the same story, but yeah, you're
running the same Like for instance, how
many times have you heard the whole I
was ridiculously fat. I had an
embarrassing moment. It made me feel
really sad. So I went through this
entire process, came out the other side,
now I have these diet pills that
basically is secretly discovered that is
going to do X, Y, and Z with scientific
terms, and now you can buy loads of
them. Like how which ad am I describing
right now?
>> You couldn't tell me cuz like there's
like 50 of them that this [laughter]
could Yeah. They all apply to the same
story.
>> Yeah. So the story is one thing but it's
knowing how to actually differentiate
between all of them. So for instance
it's not so much um and this is where
the creative strategy comes in. You look
at the creative itself like what is the
story? What is the hook? What is the
angle? What is the audience listening
to? What part of the market are we not
speaking to? So if everyone is all about
weight loss and they're like well I was
fat and disgusting. I want to be hot and
sexy.
>> Well instead of doing that look at it
from a different angle. for instance,
especially with your target demographic.
Um, cuz not all ages are the same, not
all body types are the same.
>> So, um, you can target down onto the
ectomorph, endomorph, messomorph body
types, which is quite simply have you,
uh, if you're the type person that no
matter what you do, no matter what you
eat, your body stays forever skinny and
it annoys you because you can't build
muscle.
And this is and you end up in a term
called skinny fat. because you're skinny
fat, this is how it impacts you and this
is how your life is different. And then
you talk to that demographic
specifically, but you don't do the same
thing. You find where else they're
feeling it. For instance, is it
affecting their confidence on dates? Is
it affecting their confidence in the
gym? Are they being uh bullied because
they they look all tall and gangly? Are
they not is there how do I put this? Do
they not have that deep powerful
resonant resonance and confidence that
is projected because they don't feel
comfortable in their body because they
feel so skinny? And you can actually
talk about this in the copy and say,
well, all of these issues are solved by
understanding that you have a skinnier
body type and to get that body into
shape, you need to activate this thing
that gets you over the line and it's the
thing we're selling you.
>> Yeah.
>> And that's how you move it forward. So
that's how you look at it as okay,
that's the creative aspect. Now the
strategy is how do I put that message in
front of the right people? You can be
like, well, I'm going to buy ads. I'll
do this. I'll do that. Well, everyone
else is doing that. Look at the
marketplaces that aren't being spoken
to. And we used to have this idea. I
don't hear it often as much anymore, but
it does exist. Who in your audience,
like what other hobbies do they have
that you can show up in? For instance,
if they're skinny, like going into the
skinny fat person who wants to get in
shape, what's their martial art? Are
they weightlifting? Are they a runner?
Are they into yoga? Do they do
pilateses? Are they a Comic-Con geek?
Are they a video game nerd? Are they an
anime fan? And you start looking at
those different areas that you can
target them in because they're not
they're not being targeted in those
areas. M
>> so when you go to that marketplace
that's a whole different demographic of
people that actually hit that same um
that hit that same audience. So you go
to that place and you talk about what it
is now you end up with a fresh place
where there's where they're not
expecting it. So, if everyone's running
it on Meta and Instagram, um, and then
what you're, you know, specifically
targeting this kind of person, if you
hit them up at an anime convention or at
a yoga studio or even if it is through
Meta or any of the other ad platforms,
but it's specifically talking about it
on their interests for yoga or for anime
or for video games or for whatever it
is, you massively stand out. Like, you
literally hit them in places they're not
expecting. M
>> and this basically gives you a
differentiation and that differentiation
helps over. The other one that we can do
is you can rent lists. People don't
think about this anymore. You can rent a
list from someone who is for instance if
they're in the dating market. I've got
massive dating niche list. You know this
that the other. Great. Well, that list
needs to know how to make money. So, how
about you pitch my make money offer to
that list? Or you know what? I've made
loads of money but I'm lost in love.
Great. I'm lost in love and I've got
money but my health is absolutely [__]
Okay. My health is absolutely wonderful.
My relationship is great, but I don't
know how to make money. I I know how to
make money. My health is really good,
but my dating life is absolutely [__]
Do you see how it constantly plays off
each other? And there's a myriad of
different ways you could play this. Most
people don't even think about this.
>> I've seen like a lot of copyriters,
now you know, creative strategists, just
use the right name for them. Um, you
know, I've seen all these creative
strategists, um, they they do split
tests or like they do variations on the
hook, but they're approaching it from
like a copyrightiting standpoint. So,
for example, like, hey, if you're
struggling with this thing, here's what
would happen if you take this thing for
30 days. Let's just say for example,
that sentence, they will be like, okay,
how do I create a variation? Try this
for 30 days and see what happens to your
body. Like, it's the same hook though.
It's just like re they just rewrite the
words to to describe that hook. But what
you're saying is like completely
different frame. It's like okay, how do
we call out that that audience that's
not being spoken to that that really
wants to buy this and like how do we
actually focus on the actual niche or
avatar, you know, whatever the word is
that you're using as your as a marketer.
>> How do we call them out? And that's kind
of more of what you're looking at at the
beginning of the process. And that that
seems to check that that um checks out
with all the people I've talked to that
uh making like 50 60k a month with
creative strategy just for what it's
worth, you know? Um is like all the guys
I'm talking to, they always focus on
like variable testing with like um the
avatar call outs like how do we talk to
the right person in the ads and actually
optimize them? And then of course the
strategy part that comes into that is
like
>> Yeah, as you were saying. Yeah. But
yeah, I just thought that was
interesting because it's not about the
hook and rewriting the words.
>> It's really about how do you actually
figure out the person that you're
talking to and actually talk to people
that aren't being talked to.
>> Exactly. I'll give you guys an example
that I can talk about because a case
study I have which is um there was a
supplement a collagen supplement company
in uh Germany which is doing absolutely
fan fucktantastically right now. Like
I'm actually impressed at how like since
they sold the company and they still
retained some level of ownership, but it
was launched by two copyriters. Um,
essentially what it did was they did the
launch and they had four launches prior,
but every time they did a launch with
the same hook, angle and copy with
variations of what it was, they would
lose about €200,000 every single time.
So like the first launch did 900,000 and
second launch did 700,000 third launch
did like 500,000 fourth launch did like
300,000 and they were like okay we need
to find a new way of selling to them. So
again this is creative strategy in play
while I was having the conversation with
them with my writing partner in Germany
cuz again I don't speak German but the
copy was in German. It was basically
understanding how can you translate that
over and we'll touch upon different
audience spaces as well and what you can
do because this is something that most
people don't do and it's something you
can look into. Um essentially what we
did was like while we were speaking to
them all I said was your demographic and
like it's women between 45 and 55 years
old and uh this is what it was like okay
let me just have a look at something. I
quickly looked at the type of collagen
they were producing because it's like it
wasn't like run-of-the-mill. They
actually had testing service. They
really put in the time, effort, and
capital into finding a good collagen
supplement and provider. So, it was very
above board the way they were doing
their testing. [snorts]
And what I found was what they were what
they were creating as a collagen
supplement actually affected women who
are going through pmenopause and
menopause. And then you realize, oh
[__] Okay, the average human starts
losing about 1.5% of collagen every year
after they're 25.
>> Okay, so that's insane to begin with,
but why is it the me men don't lose as
much collagen and we age differently to
women? Well, because when women go
through pmenopause and menopause, they
start going from a 1.5% like loss per
year to five or 6% a year of collagen
loss, the reserves. So that's hugely
different. So of course, their body's
not producing as much. Yeah,
>> that affects them in a multitude of
different ways. And having more collagen
supplements actually helps them go
through the hot flashes and or hot
flashes, if you will, and all the other
like the hot and cold, the itchy skin,
all the other stuff that happens is all
down to collagen and skin elasticity.
So, we just rewrote the entire hook and
angle specifically targeted to women who
are going through u menopause and
permenopause.
>> Now, the audience wasn't segmented cuz
we had like 20% of that audience was
men. So, yes, we did burn some of that
list. I will put my hands up. We could
have done better, but at the same time,
and some women wrote back going, "This
is way too on the nose. How dare you?"
Blah, blah, blah. Great. But it resulted
to like €700,000 uh in sales or €710,000
in sales. So, we got the second highest
like launch day for them. And we did it
inside a 10day window. So, we didn't
even have that much time to actually put
this together. Like, we got off the
call, they're like, "We're launching in
2 weeks. It's in German. How quickly can
you get the copy done?" So, I had to
write the copy within 3 days, have it
translated to German, have it to the
graphic designer, have it ready with the
products and shipped out in that time
period. Had we had a little bit more
time, I think we could have done better.
But, you know, not not a bad result. But
what I'm getting at here is
look at how we identified who the target
demographic was and what was not being
spoken about our product. What is it
that we were solving that our product
wasn't speaking about? And then you put
that front and center. And that's how
you find a creative strategy. So think
about that. It's it's really easy to do.
And there's things with languages
because again, Matt, you speak how many
languages? I think that like you're a
polygot, so you speak a few.
>> It's dwindling every year because I'm
not practicing.
But
>> but it's five. Yeah, it's five.
>> Yeah, cuz I remember when we were in
Spain and I was like, dude's just
busting out the Spanish like it's
nothing.
>> Yeah, it's cool. I I uh I enjoyed it. It
was what I was doing in my teens before
copyrighting is learning languages. So
languages are powerful. But here's where
something like just as an idea for
people. If you're a creative strategist
right now and you have a client product
who's again facing a lot of uh
competition in that marketplace because
what it is,
>> try marketing the same product in a
different language because not everyone
speaks English as their first language.
>> Yeah.
>> So translate it over and you might see
your results go through the roof.
Spanish is a great one, by the way, and
so is Italian. Um, I remember years ago,
and this is like it's no no longer the
case because people cottoned on to it,
but it's still heavily underserved. Um,
first it was Italian. I remember there
were three super affiliates I knew who
were in Italy who were like killing it
because they were like, "We have zero
other products in Italy and we only have
like five products to promote." So, we
were just taking everything, translating
over to Italian and selling it to our
audience. The second was a bunch of guys
in in Brazil. They were taking like
massive copywriting courses and
advertising courses and then just
translating them over into Brazilian
Portuguese, writing the sales copy in
Brazilian Portuguese and then they were
just selling that stuff as a licency to
the original. So they would send the
original owner a license agreement to be
like, "Hey, can you come in and actually
help us and do whatever it is, but it's
all in Brazilian. It's all in Brazilian
Portuguese." So they were basically just
selling millions of dollars based on
being able to license this product and
then ship it into a different language.
I mean I'm doing this right now with one
of my own and I think you were just
about to jump in and say what you where
your mind was going with this.
>> Yeah, there's a there's a brand I was
chatting to in Dubai recently and um
they're in another market that doesn't
speak English as well and their CPA is
so much lower. It's like cra it's it's
way lower. They're getting such a great
deal there. They're making so much money
in this other market and I don't think
it really matters where that is, you
know? Like I could share it, but they're
they're like big brand and stuff, but
like they're they've tapped into like a
very specific niche. Um they found a
separate audience. It's all translated
into that language and they're making a
crap ton of money. And I just think that
um yeah, that like if you look into this
kind of thing, this is also the stuff
that strategists would think about. It's
like even thinking about it and and like
cons considering it is I mean it's kind
of like you're basically a you're
basically like a marketing director
without being a manager I guess you
could say right it's like it's like
copyriter here I mean the new definition
like writer assistant basically um then
you have like creative strategist is
somebody that does the management and
you have somebody that does like the
media buying and then that those people
have let's say like editors and stuff
that like complement And then you have
like marketing director that runs that
whole department. But that the marketing
director could essentially do most of
those things, right? So it's like that's
the ascension path is like you're
basically doing what the marketing
>> director would do without um
>> doing management, you know, and even the
marketing director could just delegate
that to a project manager or a marketing
manager or something
>> and basically just be a creative
strategist. like the guy I was chatting
with um so and so made multi8 figures
was chatting with him and I was chatting
with the CMO and I asked the CMO what do
you do on a day-to-day basis because
it's a pretty impressive operation and
he's like yeah um I write copy and I was
like okay so you're a copywriter he's
like yeah yeah we're copyriters I'm like
oh yeah okay so he's a copywriter and I
was like so then how do you run the
business the marketing side of the
business because you're always writing
copy it's difficult to be in both
headspaces, you know. He's like, "Yeah,
no. I just have um a manager, marketing
manager. They run the whole like
execution. I just say, "Here's what we
want to do." I go and write the copy and
then the manager runs that whole
department that actually sets it up. But
he just basically does all the creative
strategy. Let's call it that. You know,
he just does all the creative strategy
and they produce I don't know 30 or $50
million a year profit. It's not bad.
>> Not bad at all. I mean like the so if
>> if you really want to have a great idea
of what a good creator strategist is or
who a great creator strategist
strategist is
uh in real life David Oglevie is like
the number one person that comes to mind
>> but the number two if you're looking at
fiction is Don Draper who was based on
David Oglevie like Don Draper is like
from Madman he is the definition of a
creative strategist well he's a
copywriter no he's a creative strategist
just because if you look at what he
does, he comes up with ideas and then
pitches the idea and then has his
department create the idea.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> That's the level up you got to go with.
Now, I call that a profit finder as
well. Like if cuz there's a multitude of
different hats you can wear and you and
I have discussed this because I like to
run around. I'm basically the the quote
from the Joker is I'm a dog chasing
cars. I just love I love it for the
game. Like literally, it's just for the
game that I love it.
But I feel like a lot of people don't
they're looking at it for just the money
and they never see beyond and that's the
reason they're stuck in the way they're
they're doing things. If you go beyond
those things and really look at what's
happening outside of it, outside that
scope, you will have far more fun with
it and you'll actually make a lot more
money as well as consequence because
you'll actually see things differently.
you become more useful as well for
different companies because they can't
fire you because they're like, "Hold on,
this is the person who came up with a
strategy, understood the copy, helped us
do the execution, helped us understand
the execution, and really kind of knows
everything that goes on together and how
it works hand in hand.
>> Yeah, they're invaluable to us."
>> So, over the last year, I've seen
something I've never seen before.
Copyriters and marketers, they're making
more money than ever before, especially
the top 1%. And if you want to be one of
them and you want to join us and you
want to get, you know, insights into
exactly what's happening in our industry
and also get my raw and unfiltered
thoughts, the stuff that we're not
sharing here on YouTube, then apply to
join my email list at
list.copyrighting.org.
And uh yeah, I'll see you in my next
email. Now, let's get back to the video.
Yeah, I think that this is a really good
point because many creative strategists
right now that are doing creative
strategy work, they have like a certain
defined scope every week of stuff that
they're doing and it's like most of it's
um just with ad variations, let's say on
meta and they're doing like different
concepts and different variations and
they're briefing editors. That's the
current scope. But if you've been in the
copyrightiting world for 5 to 10 years
or more, cycles change and the scope and
the actual workflows change and as tools
evolve and things change, like this is
not going to be the same workflow
forever. Like right now, that's that's
the workflow many creative strategists
have. But if you just say, "No, that's
all I do is like you know what what um
Adeline Matthew are talking about. It's
not really as as relevant to like the
thing I'm doing." It's like, yeah, but
bro, you're in the trenches of this very
very very specific workflow and it's
working, but if you want to take a step
back and be like a holistic holistically
good at marketing in general, so that as
this this workflow evolves and changes a
little bit, it's easy to adjust. Like I
mean, I can talk from my own experience,
you know, I um I started mostly in info,
right? And I was coaching I was doing um
copy writing copy for coaches in info
doing a lot of email marketing a lot of
short form like social stuff organic um
YouTube YouTube titles as well YouTube
descriptions. Kind of funny that now
I've got my own YouTube channel when one
of the first things I was doing was
writing YouTube titles. But um you know
I uh I did a lot of that that sort of
info stuff and a lot of business
coaching stuff and I um yeah just sure
enough that skill transferred because
but the workflow changed like it used to
be like that. Then I went freelance and
when I went freelance my workflow
completely changed. The way I I managed
everything was different. The way I
reported was different. The way I led
the relationship with clients changed.
Then I went from being just a freelancer
at like six figures to coaching people
multi6 figures like as a freelancer and
then also multi6 figures from coaching
like at the same time. Um workflow
changed to be at multi6 figures and then
all my coaching mentees started
essentially like solving so many
problems that I kind of learned all
their workflows and it like the workflow
just keeps changing. Like I don't think
I've had the same workflow for more than
6 months in my career. And I think for
many people that's very um that's very
difficult, right? Because it's like you
spend so many years learning this skill.
And there's I know a lot of people
they're very like
>> I think you and I are a little bit morea
like we kind of don't mind chaos. Like
as the chaos comes it's like yeah
whatever I can I can flow with that
chaos. But there are some people that
are a lot more process driven and they
like this rigidity and they create a
false sense of certainty for themselves
by relying on this workflow and system
and it just kind of stays the same and
then it's like this is what's happened
with a lot of the email copyriters in
our space. They're still like,
>> "No, I'm a list manager, you know,
that's all I do." And it's like, bro,
people are not hiring list managers,
man. Like, go Google it. If you Google
on
>> if you search on Twitter hiring or X
hiring a list manager, you get a couple
of old job descriptions, couple here and
there. If you search looking for
creative strategist, you'll get like 30
from the last two weeks. So, you could
just look at the data and it's like,
well, why is the rigidity why is that
person still doing list managements?
because they're not flexible with their
workflow. But I think it's deeper. I
think it's what you're saying. It's like
they're too attached to like the details
of the process and the nuances that they
can't zoom out and see like the bigger
picture, which is what we're talking
about. Like what is somebody that's
actually doing credit strategies is um
what's his name? Don Draper, right? The
>> Yeah, Don Draper.
>> Yeah, there you go.
>> Adman.
>> So that's the actual high level
perspective you should have is like
that's your identity. That would be
cool. like we should create a we should
create, [clears throat] you know, like
an admin admin accelerator and we're
just sitting there. We got like the
sunglasses on and we got like the suits
and we have like the the the cigar bench
and all that stuff and just like have
>> that would be kind of funny. I think
that will work
>> and but the thing is like we're coming
we're coming full circle and people
don't realize it. Like this is the
thing. We're coming full circle to what
an original copyriter was.
>> Yeah, it's nice
>> because that's what the that's what the
audience want. Now, don't get me wrong.
Have I fallen victim to the whole idea
of being very rigid and things? Yes, of
course I have because there's some
things that I'm just very rigid and and
annoying about because I, you know, I'm
used to it, but I do still evolve. It
might take me a little bit longer, but I
do do it. And it's like kind of like um
I remember when we were having this
discuss discussion last year, we spoke
about this either on the show or we did
it like privately. We were talking about
how AI is really changing everything and
how everyone really wants AI, AI, AI.
And now what you're realizing is most
people have actually used AI enough to
be like, "Yeah, AI is not producing the
results we need." Like all our stuff is
like dropping down. We need these people
back in who understand it. Because
>> Mhm.
>> It's like I said, human nature is lazy
by by design, but more importantly, it
doesn't see itself far ahead enough.
like it just doesn't look that far ahead
because you can't be like um it's the
equivalent of I'm going to turn my my
plane into purely AI with zero pilot on
the plane and then wonder why my plane
is about to crash. Well, it's because
the AI knows what to do, but you need a
manual driver behind it in order to
understand how to actually make the
adjustments, make them on the fly,
whatever happens. If the AI fails, then
there's a manual captain right there to
actually override take over. And most
businesses and most uh creative
strategists don't think that way. I
mean, don't get me wrong, creative
strategy is wonderful, but what's going
to end up happening is, and this is the
real warning for everyone, you're going
to have a lot of people saying that
they're creative strategists, but they
have no idea what it is. They'll come
into the marketplace, they'll charge a
shitload of money, they won't be able to
deliver the result, and then as a
result, everyone who is a good creative
strategist will get [__] over because
the client has been burned.
>> Yep.
>> So, do yourselves a favor, get really
good at this, and charge more money, by
the way, as a creative strategist if
you're good as one. Like, char but add
what if they doesn't matter if they
don't. If you put your prices up and
your client can't pay it or like the
people you're pitching can't pay it,
find a middle ground and get in with
them so they actually remember who you
are and what you're doing.
>> Also, make sure that if you're producing
any content, cuz again, content is king
and really does matter in today's day
and age. Literally talk about the
differences of what you do versus what
others do because you'll find a lot of
people opportunistic. A lot of people
are really opportunistic and they'll be
like, "Hey, yeah, so um I I remember
this with copywriters like again about
uh 10 11 years ago when copy became more
of a niche secret skill and then became
a widespread bisop. Um
I was competing with people who were
charging like 15 to $20,000 to write a
sales letter who had never written a
sales letter before, by the way. They
only did it because they had like Yeah.
I literally had this like um Because at
the time I was charging way less because
again I was still dealing with my own
insecurities. I was like okay I can
charge like $10,000 for a sales letter.
This is fine. I'd come in and speak to
someone like yeah we just paid someone
like 20 grand to write a sales piece and
it was absolutely [__] and now we have
no money to pay anyone else. And then
you look up that person and you're like
that dude's been writing for two weeks
and you paid him 20 grand. He's like
yeah who's a really good salesman. I was
like okay you're an idiot. That's what
all I'm hearing is that you did not do
your due diligence
>> cuz like the thing is at the re at the
end of the day build that portfolio and
have that conversation with people and
as a creative strategist keep a [__]
portfolio.
>> Yeah.
>> Like show what you've done differently.
And I think you said this on and thank
you again because I finally got the
video downloaded. Um was the gurus and
mentors to look at and the ones to
avoid. And I think one of the things
that you said about mine was uh having
someone prove that they can do what they
do completely off the cuff.
>> Yeah.
>> Get good at proving stuff off the cuff
because that as as someone who's hiring
a creative strategist or if you're a
business owner watching this, get them
to prove it. And if they're like, "Oh, I
don't do it. I don't I don't prove
things for free." I'm like, "You don't
ask them to prove it free. Give them a
hypothetical. And don't do the sell me
this pen [__] but really give them
an actual situation."
>> Yeah. [__] that. That Jordan belt. Like
the Wolf of Wall Street is [__]
responsible for so many people like,
"Sell me,
>> sell me this pen."
>> Anytime someone does that to me face to
face, I just take their pen from them
and walk away. And they're like, "Hey,
but my pen." I'm like, "You can buy it
back from me." That's it.
>> That's pretty good. Yeah. I think this
is I think this is a this is a big part
of the problem now. Um that it's always
it's the same thing with every cycle.
Like I was saying this last year. I I
have it on recording. You can go watch
one of my old videos for anyone
listening that's going to say like, you
know, that that disagrees with this. I
said it last year in like November,
October. I think I even probably said it
with you live when we were doing one of
our coaching calls from for the dojo. I
was just saying like 2026 is going to be
about who you know. And the reason it's
going to be about who you know is
because all of this AI trend has removed
a barrier of entry. But at the same
time, it's increased the the skepticism
acceleration of the market. And these
trends are going to go away very quickly
where like the the AI stuff that's
working is not going to perform for more
than a couple of weeks or maybe a month.
And it's going to go back to the
fundamental universal structures that
work in ads. And then everybody's going
to be like, well, we don't want to
create a strategist that um has no
experience and everybody's going to want
a lot of experience. And the the
requirements of entry are going up with
business owners now. Like last year um I
remember in the dojo we were closing
like some copers didn't even have any
any ecom experience in their CV.
Nothing. They didn't even position
themselves as anything. They just called
themselves credit strategist and ecom
founders were hiring them. And obviously
we we trained them well and they've
delivered and they're still working in
the industry and now they have more
data. But this year it's like I'm
getting a lot of people say like, "Oh,
you know, I can't break in cuz every
single application's asking for ecom
experience." It's like, yeah, well
that's because because people keep going
in and overcharging and don't know what
they're doing and then they burn
business owners and now business owners
are like, "Don't bother applying unless
you have two to three years of
experience."
>> And actually, we were even talking about
this back when we were doing that one
promotion, right? We were doing a
promotion um for one of my offers back
in January, I think this year.
>> Yeah,
>> we were doing that. We were talking
about like, hey, if you you know, if you
don't jump in now,
>> 90day window,
>> there's a 90-day window. That window is
closed where there was like you could
get in all this stuff that specific
stuff is
>> that as an aside, by the way, that would
be a great promotion for your list to
actually tell them about this and be
like, "Hey, by the way, remember I told
you this would be 90 days from now?"
Well, it took less time. And it did take
less time. It was only 60 days. like
within two months of this year, by
March, all the creative strategy roles,
all the stuff for the ecom, they were
like, "No, no, you need experience to
actually come in and talk to us."
>> Yeah. They all want it now. So now what
you got to do if you're listening to
this and you're like, "Oh, no, what do I
do?" It's like, "Well, if you do have
experience in info in other industries,
you can reposition it and talk about it
and translate it in a way that makes
sense to ecom." like consumer brand, you
know, I got experience working with
consumer brands or I have experience
with uh new customer acquisition, you
know, like these kinds of words or like
life life cycle marketing. What other
things would you suggest to people that
want to break into the space that have a
background in cooperating, but they're
they're they're finding themselves up
against this like experience barrier or
um results. Show us this and that.
>> Show them your results. Like the look,
all you got to be able to do the only
way I managed to write for like 433
odd different niches, markets, and
industries, which is by the way, how the
[__] do you do that? Well, you just keep
talking to them. And they're like, what
do you mean? Like I don't sell like I
tell people I don't write for niches. I
write for humans.
>> And it's one of my favorite quotes by
Jav Spectre. It's in my notepad. It's
don't play the don't play the odds, play
the man. And what that means is
>> look at human nature. play the human
nature card. Like what I do is I help
people create I help create buying
situations or facilitate buying
situations. That's actually what I do. I
put the right offer in front of the
right person at the right time with the
right wording with the right advertising
to get them to say yes. Well, have you
done that as a copywriter? Well, have
you done it for ecom? Yes. Have you done
it for if you've never done it for ecom
for instance, have you done it for and
all your stuff is in info for instance
like coaching and info. How do you
actually move that over? Well, have you
helped your client retain more sales
from their mailing list? Yes. Great.
Have you helped your client increase
their sales to their mailing list? Yes.
Have you written ads that brought in
customers? Yes. Have you positioned your
client in a way that basically makes
them stand out in the marketplace that's
very, very crowded? Yes. Talk about
Excuse me. Talk about those things. M
>> talk about how like I'll give you a
video that I'm going to be shooting
later today cuz I think it's a great
idea is quite simply
one of the things I've done differently
is um positioning it well if you're you
know if you're in for a personal brand
it could be I positioned what was it I
helped my clients stand out in a very
saturated overcrowded market and
actually sell over a million dollars
inside a 90-day window
>> and now bringing that over to ecom where
you guys are far more open. You have far
less competition. You have far more like
the the boundary of skepticism is that
the results and benefits are far more
tangible because I was selling
intangible stuff.
>> Now I'm selling tangible. [laughter]
>> Yeah. Like that's literally what you're
doing.
>> It's a really good argument.
>> Like like that's what I was selling. Oh,
I was so good at writing info. Yeah. you
are selling digital products and
coaching that literally had no results
that you could actually like look at
because humans are so diverse in how
they apply things that they themselves
may not be able to get actually get the
results. So for instance um like I know
I'm elite at what I do. It's because I
have trained some of the best copyriters
you'll find out and some of the best
marketers out there and Matthew you've
seen me do this with a lot of people.
You see the improvements
that happens. So, I'm still teaching. I
I can still show people how to do that
result, but even then, I can be like,
"Yeah, but there's some people who never
applied what I said to them because of
human laziness and human error." Uh, go
there's still a failure rate that's
going to be affected in what we do no
matter how good I am. Even Tony Robbins
has a failure rate.
Whereas, if I'm selling a supplement, if
I'm selling shoes, if I'm selling a
neutropic, if I'm selling a sleep aid,
if I'm selling something, a piece of
clothing, if I'm selling something that
is physically tangible, [laughter] it's
so much easier to describe those
benefits because I'm like,
>> in two weeks, you will be holding my
product in your hand. You'll be able to
look at it and show it off to your
friends. You can't be like, "Hey, look
at my coaching."
>> There's nothing there. like you can't
invite your friend over to look at your
new coaching program and um like the
results that you're getting from your
coaching program. It's very very
difficult to show that and explain it.
Whereas if you sell someone like I don't
know uh custommade
um I don't know custom made uh teacups
that have like really funky designs on
you like hey man look at my really cool
design that I've got this this is like
selling millions or uh my friend Dan who
is an incredible copyright turned ecom
business owner he sells candles
but for a very specific niche
>> and you can smell his candles that's a
physical tangible product
>> and this is one thing people don't
realize it. And by the way, that's
something that you should have um if
you're struggling right now with info,
like, oh, how do I get clients? I worked
in info last 5 years, whatever it is,
>> or coaching or any of the spaces that
you were in that were basically
non-tangible results. The game just got
so much easier for you. Like, pitch your
clients this way. Hey guys, I was
selling air. I was selling ice to
Eskimos. That's what I was doing. I was
selling air to humans.
>> I was selling water to fish.
Like that's what I was doing. Oh, how'd
you do that? Well, I was telling people
how to do this, that, the other. Oh,
that's pretty cool. Why do you want to
do ecom? Well, because yours is so much
easier to do than the other thing. Why?
I have a physical tangible product that
I can point at results in. The thing
arrives, you apply it, and you see a
result.
>> What do you mean deodorant? Like, there
was a company I was pitching recently
that literally did do that. They sell
deodorants
>> like and stuff, but their audience is
>> their audience was teenage boys. Like
their audience was like selling to moms
who have smelly teenage development boys
who are going through body odor issues
and they're like you need to sell them
this like okay uh traditional like
what's called aerosol cans or like
whatever it is or ax or links or
whatever it is. Um that deodorant is
harmful to their body because it's
mass-produced. We have a very natural
version that's really really good for
them that won't make them smell bad and
won't damage their skin long term. Buy
it from us.
>> It arrives. Give it to your child. If
they don't like it within the first week
and they don't smell better, send us the
thing back and we'll give you a money
back. You now have instant stakes. They
don't have to wait 90 days to see a
result.
>> They can day one, oh, this smells
amazing. Great. I've now I'm now a
customer for life.
>> Like,
>> yeah,
>> it's so [__] easy. It's so [__]
easy. And I'm saying this out loud to
someone that's realizing this as well of
how in how simple this is going to be.
>> It really is because like the other
thing is all the data that's already
been like validated for like the unique
selling point because with info
>> it's like the unique selling point is
very very dependent on like the
mechanism that you've used to to set up
to set the opportunity up, right? You
have to like mentally set up, oh, this
is an opportunity for you and here's how
you're going to benefit, you know? Um,
whereas with ecom,
>> if it's a physical product, it's like
there's a USP and there's a builtin
mechanism in the in the I don't know the
compound that they use in the spray or
whatever it is. It's like that that
product's very unique patent or whatever
they they they're doing to sell it. It's
not like it's going to change. It's not
like an info where you have to change
the mechanism every two three months.
you know, you can potentially re
restructure the selling mechanism, but
like
>> with info, it's like I have to
constantly re resell the opportunity and
say like, "Hey, here's why this is the
best opportunity today." Whereas later,
it's not going to be there. And then 3
months later, you have to come up with a
whole new funnel, a whole new belief
shift sequence, whole new mechanism. I
find with ecom, of course, there's other
challenges. There's other things like
tapping into broader markets and finding
pockets of customers and that's a whole
different skill for sure than info.
>> Um you can apply an info too but like
the mechanism from the USP onwards a lot
of the time feels very s simple and very
similar
>> and a lot of the time it's just about
like how do we find that that like that
lead that has the broadest market.
That's really it. It's like figuring out
that big hook and that lead and then
like a few different variations of that,
like a few dimensionalizations, blah
blah blah blah blah. It's not that
complicated. Like I I don't find it that
difficult. I actually found writing
email copy and info harder than this.
Like I
>> Yeah,
>> I'm re I'm reviewing emails um and I'm
like, oh, you know, I'm sitting and
reviewing the email for 20 minutes with
like with a piece of creative strategy
like a a brief or a UGC script or
something. I'm reading it. like, yeah,
this lead, you're not calling out the
audience um in in a a unique way. The
previous script, you had the exact same
call out. Like, maybe twe tweak that,
tweak the lead a little bit. Try this
different dimensionalization. Test it
and tell me how the data goes. Like,
done. Like 5 minute review. Meanwhile,
email like you need to change this, you
need to change this, you need to change
this. Here's how you redo the clothes.
like
>> you know
>> it's the best description I can have for
you guys is circa 2014 to 2019 like
5year stretch
>> where every we were we were I remember
talking to a few of my friends where
they were like yeah dude if you stop
selling to marketers and just start
selling to regular people you will make
way more money and I was like what do
you guys mean they're like marketers
know all the tricks so you now need to
pull out new tricks and new secrets and
new things that they haven't seen before
>> whereas selling to an everyday person
who has never seen this [__] they're
Holy [__] this is like magic. What are
you doing? This is so incredible. And
you're like,
>> yeah, that's just really basic. So with
UGC scripts and like even ecom stuff,
they are using a fraction of what we
actually know and know how to use. Like
I was talking to someone about this. We
were they were doing um they were asking
me how do I sell more stuff to my
audience like to my to my client's
audience. I read the emails. Not one of
them had a story whatsoever attached to
it. So I was like, "Just try that."
They're like, "What do you mean?" Like,
"Just try adding a story here."
>> And so they were like, "What do you
mean?" I was like, "Well, the entire
pitch that you are sending out is here's
the thing that we have. Here's why it's
discounted. Go buy it right now." And
there's no reasons. There's no benefits.
There's no nothing. And the benefits are
like one sentence. The benefit is like,
let's take the deodorant thing as an
example. It's like smell better. Um,
make your child not stink up the house.
It's like literally that level of like
dumbness. So when we start going like um
you know we did a testimonial for one of
their people was like let's say again
deodorant as an example would be this is
James it's like uh what was it James
couldn't get James couldn't get a date
until dot dot dot and the email would be
like so we got this email from one of
our customers who basically said their
son James had had a really hard time
getting on dates like every time he'd go
out he'd have a great time and he'd be
like really really happy but then he
would come home and wonder why his date
would never call him back and I kept and
it and it didn't really dawn on me that
his natural bo until like he sat down
and I talked to the girl and she was
like, "I really like him, but he just
smells really bad." Like I I hope we can
do something about this, but we don't
really know. Um again, I'm shooting this
off the fly right now.
>> Yeah. And it was the whole thing was
just talking would been talking about
how this kid's bo was so bad and how
like once they actually started using
our products, James started to actually
see an improvement in his dating life,
his confidence. Uh our natural products
are our deodorant 100% natural. So it
doesn't damage his skin naturally. It
doesn't cause any production hormonal uh
changes what he needs. Uh it's healthy
and friendly for the environment. So it
means that even if he's trying to even
if he's smelling better, he's not
actually damaging the environment around
him. including his bo. Haha. And then
something else is a third point. And
then be like, "Go buy this thing right
now if you want to smell better and
actually boost your confidence." Boom.
That's your sales [__] pitch. That's
how easy that stuff is because they
don't use it. They don't use it. And
they were like, "We just did what?" Like
that's insane. Um I had this with uh one
of the guys that is in one of your guys,
Pepe. Uh, I was I was helping him out
with something and he started using like
he started using emails for his client
and I swear to God they 10xed that email
revenue
by simply adding stories.
>> 10xed
>> like
10x they were making uh without I don't
think Pepe is going to be mad about me
saying this, but they were making 8,000
a month on emails after he entered the
conversation. Just did a couple of
tweaks. They made $80,000 afterwards.
>> Think about how insane that Think about
how easy that is. The stuff that we do
on hard mode
>> is easy for us on ecom. So, you just
need to position yourself and get in
front of these people. The thing I love
about like the ecom space as well is the
worst part is that it makes they pay you
like two to three times more than info
because in info the gurus is always like
doing this bit of tug and war to try and
keep money because they don't have
equity in their business. A lot of it
like most of them don't have any equity.
It's just info. So it's always like how
do we squeeze as much as possible? How
do we get the team to work like dogs?
Obviously there's exceptions. I've love
info. Like I've been in it for like
almost a decade now. I'm getting old.
But with ecom, it's like
>> say that to me. [laughter]
>> So with with ecom, it's like, you know,
they they've
they're scaling for either an exit or to
get into retail to distribute like
across America or whatever their play
is. It's not a money. It's not like an
instant cash play. It's a it's a growth
play. It's a let's scale the revenue.
And I think that that kind of psychology
coupled with ads when you're used to
spending 10 to $100,000 a day in ads,
what is 10k a month to have a creative
strategist like sit in the account and
actually create some winners that you
can spend hundreds of thousands of
dollars on?
>> It's not a lot of money for them, right?
>> Even a creative consultant who's getting
paid 10 grand a month just to basically
look over stuff and be like, "Yeah, no,
do it this differently. Do this
differently. Do this differently. Stand
out this way. Do this other thing. Make
your life a lot easier." And by the way,
just to go back to this point,
that company that I worked with in
Germany, they sold for 165 million, by
the way, just to give you an idea. They
sold like and it started by two
copyriters. The two copyriters like
walked away with like well over like 30
million a piece.
>> That's pretty good
>> of this.
>> Damn. And they recently just they s they
signed a very big celebrity
>> in this like right now as their
spokesperson and their creative market
because this person now jumped ship
because they're like I can do creative
marketing they can't but whatever they
have a big name. Going back to it what
I'm going to say though is that you
could the way that you pitch these
clients from now on just as an idea.
Don't pitch them like info product
clients. Pitch them as you would anyway
and have a conversation. Hell, even go
ahead and like I remember Shiv, shout
out to Shiv Shetty, uh I know he's no
longer in the space, but like he's a
really really good dude who had his
process where he would be like, "Look,
I'll just send you a couple of emails
for free up front. You can test them. If
you like them, then we can work
together."
>> You can do almost the same thing with
ecom and be like, "Hey, listen. I' I've
got a couple of emails. Test them out
with your audience. Let me know what you
think." Oh, this works really well.
Great. Hire me. How much do we hire you
for? 10 grand a month. Thank you. And
they're like, "All right, cool. you've
what are your responsibilities and then
you basically write out the scope and
the beauty is yes you will be paying
you'll be making you'll be doing a lot
more work let's just put it that way
you'll be doing more work
>> but you will get paid a shitload more
>> oh no gets paid so much money you know
>> and it's not even more work in the way
that it's where it used to be like so
I'll give you an idea and this is a
belief that I had to shift in myself and
for for one of my dudes
>> was um
>> so for instance if If you were told to
write a 30 email welcome sequence or a
30 email sequence for info, that's
[__] hard because you got to come
with like hooks, angles, processes, and
everything else. 30 emails for like econ
that's like those emails could literally
be one page. Those emails could
literally be like subject line, hey,
thank you for joining our mailing list.
Hey, thanks so much for joining our
mailing list. We'll be sending you some
really cool stuff. In the meantime, have
a look at this, including stories. go
buy our product if you really like it.
Take care. Thanks. Bye. And then the
next email goes into like almost the
same thing because you don't have to
sell them on a benefit or an idea of
staying active. They've already said
yes, they want the thing. You just keep
telling them why they should buy it.
>> I feel like the title of this video
should be like creative strategy is easy
when you do this.
>> I think that would be the perfect little
title for this. Like make creative
strategy easy for yourself.
>> Yeah. like it's it's not uh of course I
respect the craft and the guys that I'm
coaching they're working hard. They're
making a lot more money than they used
to make. They are working hard but it's
not difficult. It's still simple. Even
though it's hard work, it's still a
simple process. And I think that the
process in info is more complex. You
know, there's there's a lot more moving
pieces and there's a lot I I think the
learning curve is actually honestly a
lot harder in info because with ecom
it's like
>> huge.
>> You just have to understand structures.
is you have to understand like the ad
structures and like what you're breaking
down and like why you're breaking it
down. You access to data and the best
part is like you actually get access to
data in a way where you can see what's
happening on the account. Whereas a lot
of these info accounts either they don't
have their tracking properly dialed in
or they do and it's all on the media
buyer shoulders and you just kind of
following the instructions. But with
these these ecom clients, you have a lot
more like creative liberty to to kind of
look at the actual data and be like what
an actual marketer does. It's like live
in the ad account and split test stuff
and so you learn a lot quicker too. So
anyway,
>> um I know the the conversation was like
>> what exactly is the process and like how
do you break into it and now I think
we're just both selling ourselves more
and more on how simple this is.
>> It is actually so much more simple. Like
I'm like talking to you I'm kind of like
why have I been pushing this rock up
this hill so much? It's like don't just
go downhill make life easier for you.
>> Yeah. So over the last year I've seen
something I've never seen before.
copyriters and marketers, they're making
more money than ever before, especially
the top 1%. And if you want to be one of
them and you want to join us and you
want to get, you know, insights into
exactly what's happening in our industry
and also get my raw and unfiltered
thoughts, the stuff that we're not
sharing here on YouTube, then apply to
join my email list at
list.copyrighting.org.
And uh yeah, I'll see you in my next
email. Now, let's get back to the video.
>> What What do you think the the big
challenges actually are? Maybe let's go
there for a minute. Like what do you
think the actual
>> pitching
>> is it that
>> 100% pitch? Yeah, it's really pitching
and actually getting comfortable with
the amount of work that you need to do
because if you're a heavy creative and
you get put into an environment where
there's a lot of data and speaking
mostly for myself on this because again
I do like data but again it's being able
to check both. There's an element where
you feel like the new kid at the school
where you don't really know what you're
doing. But the difference is, and this
is a really big mindset shift for a lot
of people, uh, and it's one that I'm
actually realizing myself, is that
you're not the new kid at the school,
you're the new cool kid at the school.
So, you're not the new kid who's like,
I'm like shy stuff. You're like, no,
you're the new shiny kid that everyone
wants to play with the at the playground
to actually find out where you're where
you fit in the hierarchy. So, this gives
you like an in that no one else has. So,
utilize that. So for instance, if you're
thinking about, okay, I don't know data
analytics and I don't know all that
stuff, it's not difficult to watch a
YouTube video on this, like how do I
discern what it is? And as Richard
Branson likes to like his big quote is
if you don't know how to do something,
say yes and figure out along the way.
And the way that you can do that is once
you get the job, just be like, hey,
could you walk me through your data
analytics? I can just have a look at
them and see what it is and get the
person to walk you through them and be
like, "Okay, cool. So, could you send me
a couple of your previous UGC scripts so
I can see what there is or you a couple
of your emails so I can see what you're
looking for? Oh, wonderful. Thank you so
much. And then you just basically play
because a lot of the times the fear in
your head is that it's like
>> it's like info where you're expected to
know everything from the day that you
come in. Whereas this, they're a little
bit more forgiving if you just look at
their data. If you look at their stuff
and go, "Oh, I can fix this all day."
And then go play.
>> Yeah.
>> It's really shifting. I'd say it's
shifting that internally. That's one
thing. And the second is the selling
because you said right now they're
looking for two or three years of
experience in ecom. Well, you can
circumvent that by literally saying I
may not have two or three years of
experience in ecom, but what I do have
is a lifetime or I have like three or
four years in info where I'm used to
selling air to humans and basically
selling nothing. So, I would love to get
on a call with you. Can we speak for 10
minutes? And what you mean? If I cannot
get you, if I cannot show you that I
know what I'm doing inside 10 minutes,
don't hire me. In fact, send me one of
your emails that you're currently
working on and let's see what I can do.
>> Mhm.
>> Get on a call in that 10-minute phone
call. Be like, "Hey, here's my screen
share. This is the Google Doc or what
you sent me. These are the edits of how
I'd make it different. Um, and this is
why and this is the reason why." Great.
And like, oh [__]
>> that's really good, too. You can just
demonstrate live. Like, here's how I
would iterate this concept. Yeah,
because live demon there's nothing that
beats live demonstration and you know
this like you've seen me do this a bunch
of times whenever I like verbalize and
shoot copy off the hip. They're like
>> you've done it like a couple times
already on this on this interview and I
feel like it's going to be demonstration
for a lot of people. You know, they're
just going to I like just listening to
it. It's quite entertaining. One thing
you said that that's pretty good is um I
think this is quite powerful is
obviously the live demonstration but
having some samples
can also like if you say for example
like I have three to four years in info
but what I did was I had a look at your
brand and I went ahead and I put
together these three to four concepts
that I don't see you guys are currently
running to call out different avatars
that are within the same like market
demographic and I think try these and
see what they you know if you like
go ahead and run them. That could also
demonstrate that it's like, yeah, look,
I have all this experience selling air
to humans. And I went ahead and
demonstrated I know exactly how I'm
doing what I'm doing here with ecom by
just writing you some some UGC scripts
or some briefs and you can go ahead and
pass these to your team.
And uh I'll tell you what, for most of
you listening to this, it's like I maybe
it's free already somewhere, but like
even if it's not free, there's like a
couple of programs or a couple of things
out there where you can literally just
spend $100 and you can get access or
like get hooked for example. Like get
hooked is a
>> is a software, right? Like you you just
just take like a$100 $200 budget
>> and you could literally reverse engineer
and figure out what the exact you could
even pay a copyriter. could just grab
some interview that I've done with one
of the students that I've coached on
this channel and reach out to them,
$100, $200, pay them for their time, ask
them to show you the best practices of
their workflow,
and you could borrow that workflow. And
you could take the Google doc, the way
that they deliver the copy, and then you
just build your portfolio with the exact
same workflow as that. And when you show
the client, they're going to be like,
"Huh, this document looks exactly the
same in terms of formatting and design
and structure and delivery as every
single other person we work with. They
clearly know what the hell they're
doing." Like that is in itself is a live
demonstration just formatting the doc
correctly, you know,
>> correctly. Yeah,
>> there is that. And just to jump and
dovetail off the back end of what you're
saying here because it really makes
sense.
>> I've never understood this and this is a
laziness that I've noticed with a lot of
copyriters, not just in any space. And I
get it. I'm going to call it laziness,
but it could be just, oh, we're not used
to it. No one likes to practice anymore.
I don't know if you've noticed this.
They just like to live de they like to
live play. They never practice. They're
like, I'm going to practice on my
clients thing. It's like, [__]
don't do that, right?
>> Like, practice your skills when you're
not being watched. So, an idea that
really worked for me when I when I was
coming up, like the story of me writing
a,000 sales letters in a single year,
which is three and a half sales letters
a day. And again, like I said, I only
used five of them, but that gave me 995
samples to show people like, "Can I see
your portfolio?" I was like, "Yeah, here
you go." Boom. And they're like, I'd
even write at the very top, "These are
purely samples and ideas of what I can
create."
And people like, "Oh [__] you probably
had a time machine and used AI from the
future or something cuz it's like,
>> oh, definitely 100%.
>> Clearly, clearly you just did that. It's
not like my brain was the AI, but
anyway."
>> Yeah. Yeah. Um, Adel intelligence if you
will.
>> There we go. Adel.ai.
>> But going back to what we were saying,
it's if you're literally at home right
now, if you're watching this, just go
ahead and do yourself a favor. Block out
an hour. Go find an ecom business that
you would like to work for.
Either join their mailing list or look
at what they're currently doing. Go to
their ads library. Look at whatever it
is. I mean, there's so many free
resources. You can use Get Hooked if you
want to, but like Facebook ad library.
If you don't want to spend any money, go
through Facebook ad library, find who it
is, rewrite four of their ads, find
their email address from like their from
their website, mail it to them, be like,
"Hey guys, uh the subject line could
literally be looked at your ads. Here's
a couple of improvements. Hey, I'm
breaking into the ecom space right now.
I've worked in info and I've worked in
copy for absolutely years, but I am a
creative strategist and these are the
things that I do differently." Bam, bam,
bam, bam, bam. These are the things I've
done
>> attached. I couldn't help myself, but
I'm was like, I couldn't help myself.
So, I did some research on your company.
Absolutely love what you guys stand for.
Created four new ads for you. Please go
ahead and test them. Just let me know
what you think. If you like them, reply
back to me and I'll send you some more.
Take care. Speak soon. Bye. Or I've
written these things for you guys
that'll cover and just outline them.
I've written four Facebook ads that hit
different angles that you guys are
missing. Um, and I look through, I
checked if you guys have used them in
the past. You haven't actually used
these angles at all, but they actually
work because of this reason, this
reason, this reason, and this reason.
Um, just send me a quick little reply
and I will happily send it to you
because if I send it to you right now as
an attached folder, it will go straight
to spam. Um, looking forward to hearing
from you. Speak soon. Person's name.
Great idea as an example of how to get
started with that conversation. Another
conversation starter could literally be
just I'm your target demographic. Hi, I
am literally your target demographic.
This is the [__] that I buy and I don't
think you guys are selling to me
correctly. Here are three things I would
do differently if you were to pitch
people like me. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Here you go. Boom. Done.
>> It's like the easiest little win.
>> Yeah.
>> It's it's such an easy lead in like I
remember um so Vessie Shoes, Vesi shoes,
like their boots. I'm their perfect
demographic customer because like
they're waterproof shoes that are
stylish as hell. But like I don't live
in a country that's wet anymore. So I
can't use them. But I'm I'm like if I
lived in a if I lived in Germany for
instance, I'd be like, "Yeah, [__]
sign me up for some vesty shoes because
I'm the right person to pitch these cuz
I use them." Um Vibrams, Birkenstocks,
like you can pitch shoe brands if you
wanted this way just simply by saying,
"You guys are missing out on this thing.
Let me help you with it." M
>> and also keep in mind that most ecom
businesses,
most of the founders come from the world
of like how traditional shoe stores and
traditional brick and mortar businesses
run. They're not digital marketers.
They're not from our world. They know
how to use like Instagram, but they
don't know how to actually like run the
strategies.
Like if you sit down and say, "Hey, um,
so do you know who uh you're like, "Do
you know who Gary Halbbert is? Do you
know who Jay Abraham is? Do you know who
Clayton Makepiece is? Do you know who
like uh you know Lorie Morgan is? Do you
know who any of these people are? And
they're like, "No, we have no idea who
the [__] they are." And you're like, I
have such an unfair advantage over you.
>> This is good. I like this. This is This
is good. Ed'll appreciate this, man.
Ed.ai.
>> Of course.
I I think it's uh it just goes to show
like the fundamental skills translate
into anything because
you know obviously we've been doing a
lot of work together in in in the space
you know before it became a trend and
everybody started to catch on but I
their workflow that they're currently
doing in a lot of these accounts is a
little bit unique and yet I feel like
all the stuff that we've talked about
today just based on my experience
working with all these creative
strategists it's like you just dominate
like if you went in right now and you
wanted to go and I don't know put put
that hat back on and and be a copyriter
for for a year, you would you would just
completely, you know, clean the
competition up because they they're
they're just sitting there and they're
they're stuck in the in the details of
the process and they're not just
applying like differentiation. just
apply marketing to your own business. I
think is really the biggest takeaway
that I'm having here is like once you
understand the workflow and you
understand like what's required of you
as a creative strategist, which is what
we first talked about, then just apply
marketing to yourself and position
yourself differently.
>> Yeah, that's really good.
>> Yeah. Yeah, that's good.
>> Someone already owns Adel.ai.
>> Damn it.
>> Where can people find you if they want
to?
>> Sorry,
>> I was imagine it's just me, but I've
totally forgot I own this domain. It
could you could have bought him like 20
years ago, you know, when you wrote all
those sales letters, you're like, "Hey,
I'm basically an AI at this point." And
you're like, "I had a little AI. Let me
buy that real quick."
>> But yeah, to answer your question, uh
the best place you guys can find me um
easily is well, it's actually two places
actually. Just find me on Instagram,
[music] Adela. Like, if you just find me
on there, it's great. I reset my I've
started a brand new Instagram account,
so I'm actually going to be posting far
more frequently, which is what I'm
currently doing. Um I'm currently
posting twice a day on there. like so
there's a lot of information so we're
talking about life business mindset
creative strategy and everything else in
between um so yeah just hit me up on
there you'll find me a lot more easier
and if you want to check out my website
if you are cuz I do have copyriters and
marketers don't join my mailing list
please because it's not meant for you
like there is literally it won't you
won't get any benefit out of it like at
all but if you're a business owner who
is literally doing over a million
dollars a year head over tomarcy.com
[music] I do have a free report on there
that's coming out very soon cuz we're
still building out the site should be
live by the time this thing goes live
where I basically walk through the five
mistakes that you're currently making
that's costing you like hundreds of
thousand hundreds of [music] thousands
of dollars a year because you're just
blinding to them. And this is a stuff
I've seen with my clients. So go check
it out. And by the way, the more money
you make, the more money you're losing
because you're not doing the stuff.
>> Yeah.
Thanks so much, man. This has been
really fun. Really enjoyed it.
>> Thank you for having me, man. As always,
it's been a pleasure.
>> Yeah. Chat soon, bro. Take care. Take
care guys. Bye.